A Guide to the Saxon W. Holt papers, 1890-1940
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Saxon W. Holt papers, 1890-1940
The Library of Virginia
53483
.175 (1 box and 1 folder)
Saxon W. Holt
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Michael Holt, St Anselmo, California.
Biographical Information
Saxon Winston Holt was born 25 March 1871 in Surry County, Virginia, to Dr. Micajah Quincy Holt (1826-1909) and Virginia Winston Holt (d. by 1877). He attended local schools and Bethel Academy near Warrenton, Virginia. Holt worked for Butler and Boscher, wholesale tobacco manufacturers, then opened S. W. Holt and Company, wholesale grocers, in Newport News, Virginia. Elected to the Virginia Senate, Holt served from 1904 to 1937, including as president pro tempore from 1920 to 1937. He was elected lieutenant governor of Virginia in 1937 and served from 1938 until his death in 1940. Holt married Maria Davis Reynolds (1880-1974) 19 April 1904, and they had three children. Holt died in Newport News 31 March 1940 and was buried in Greenlawn Memorial Park in that city.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1890-1940, of Saxon W. Holt (1871-1940) of Newport News, Virginia, concerning his political career as a state senator and as lieutenant governor of Virginia. Papers also include personal correspondence from his father M. Q. Holt (1826-1909) and correspondence from Saxon W. Holt, Jr., (1905-1980) to his sister Maria R. Holt (Sprigg) (1909-1994). Papers also include a certificate, 31 March 1890, from Bryant and Stratton College, and the charter and bylaws of the Ragged Island Gunning Association of Virginia.
Contents List
- Papers, 1890, 1900-1910 (Folder 1)
- Papers, 1912-1919 (Folder 2)
- Papers, 1928-1930 (Folder 3)
- Papers, 1932-1940 (Folder 4)
- Lieutenant governor papers, January 1938 (Folder 5)
- Lieutenant governor papers, February 1938 (Folder 6)
- Lieutenant governor papers, March 1938, no date 1938 (Folder 7)
- Lieutenant governor papers, 1939-1940 (Folder 8)
- Saxon W. Holt, Jr., letters, 1927-1940 (Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous papers (Folder 10)
- Oversize materials located in oversize box 70 (Box Oversize box 70)